

HD STUDENT IN COMPUTER AND COMMUNICATION SCIEN

EPFL, Lausanne, Switzerland

■ sori424@gmail.com | 🏠 sori424.github.io | 🖸 sori424 | 💆 @SoyoungOh5

Interests

COMPUTATIONAL SOCIAL SCIENCE · NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING · COGNITIVE SCIENCE

My research broadly lies in the areas of human-centered computing. Specifically, I would like to advance the performance as well as the explainability of artificial intelligence based on the understanding of humans.

Education

École polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL)

Lausanne, Switzerland

Sep. 2022 -

PHD IN COMPUTER AND COMMUNICATION SCIENCES (EDIC)

Advisor: Antoine Bosselut (Expected)
 Sungkyunkwan University (SKKU)
 M.S. IN APPLIED ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

Seoul, South Korea

Aug. 2020 - Feb. 2022

Advisor: Eunil Park

• Master's Thesis: Understanding Difficulties of Content Filterings and Humans' Cognitive Bias in Algorithmic Recommendations

Sungkyunkwan University Seoul, South Korea

B.S. IN ENGINEERING, INTERDISCIPLINARY PROGRAM OF CONVERGENT SOFTWARE - SAMSUNG CONVERGENCE

Mar. 2016 - Aug. 2020

SOFTWARE COURSE

B.A. IN PSYCHOLOGY

Research Experience_

Research Intern

Georgia Institute of Technology

(Remote)

Jul. 2021 - Apr. 2022

CLAWS LAB

- Advisor: Srijan Kumar
- Engaged in survey paper on countering misinformation
- Devised natural language processing method to debunk misinformation

Undergraduate Research Assistant

SKKU

Jul. 2019 - Aug. 2020

- Data experience LabAdvisor: Eunil Park
- · Explored user experience of augmented reality and virtual reality products (Funded by NRF of Korea)
- Developed a Deep Learning Model for Predicting Service Reuse (Funded by the NRF of Korea)

Publication

j: journal · c: conference · Equal Contribution¹ · Correspoding Author*

c3 Soyoung Oh, & Eunil Park (2022).

Are you aware of what you are watching? Role of machine heuristic in online content recommendations. ICWSM 2022 Workshop on Cyber Social Threats (CySoc 2022). [PDF]

c2 Sangeun Lee¹, Soyoung Oh¹, Minji Kim, & Eunil Park (2022).

Measuring Embedded Human-like Bias in Face Recognition Models. AAAI 2022 Workshop on Artificial Intelligence with Biased or Scarce Data (AIBSD 2022). [PDF]

c1 Soyoung Oh¹, Jisu Kim¹, Seungpeel Lee.¹, & Eunil Park (2021).

Jujeop: Korean Puns for K-pop Stars on Social Media. In Proceedings of the Ninth International Workshop on Natural Language Processing for Social Media 2021, NAACL HLT'21 Workshop. [PDF]

j7 Dahye Jeong¹, **Soyoung Oh**¹, & Eunil Park (2022).

DemoHash: Hashtag Recommendation based on User Demographic Information. Expert Systems With Applications. [HTML]

j6 Soyoung Oh, Honggeun Ji, Jina Kim, & Eunil Park (2022).

Deep learning model based on expectation confirmation theory to predict customer satisfaction in hospitality service. Information Technology & Tourism. [HTML]

- j5 Honggeun Ji, Soyoung Oh, Jina Kim, & Eunil Park (2022).
 Integrating Deep Learning and Machine Translation for Understanding Unrefined Languages. CMC-Computers, Materials & Continua, 70(1), 669–678. [HTML]
- j4 Jina Kim, Honggeun Ji, Soyoung Oh, Syjung Hwang, Eunil Park, & del Pobil, A. P. (2021).
 A deep hybrid learning model for customer repurchase behavior. Journal of Retailing and Consumer Services (SSCI, JCR 2019 IF=4.219, Q2 in Business). [HTML]
- **j3** Jina Kim, Yeonju Jang, Kunwoo Bae, **Soyoung Oh**, Namjeong Jeong, Eunil Park, & del Pobil, A. P. (2021). Between comments and repeat visit: capturing repeat visitors with a hybrid approach. Data Technologies and Applications. [HTML]
- j2 Soyoung Oh, Jina Kim, Honggeun Ji, Eunil Park, Jinyoung Han, Minsam Ko, & Moonyoung Lee (2020). Cross-cultural Comparison of Interactive Streaming Services: Evidence from Twitch. Telematics and Informatics, ISSN: 0736-5853 (SSCI, JCR 2019 IF=4.139, Q1 in Information Science & Library Science). [HTML]
- j1 Jina Kim, Soyeon Shin, Kunwoo Bae, Soyoung Oh, Eunil Park, & del Pobil, A. P. (2020).
 Can AI be a content creator? Effects of content creators and information delivery methods on the psychology of content consumers.
 Telematics and Informatics, ISSN: 0736-5853 (SSCI, JCR 2019 IF=4.139, Q1 in Information Science & Library Science). [HTML]

Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistant SKKU

AAl3020, Dept. of Applied Artificial Intelligence at Undergraduate Course

Fall semester, 2020

• Led research project with undergraduate students and successfully submitted paper to conference [c2]

Instruction Assistant KINTEX, South Korea

IOT MAKER BOOTH @ E2FESTA2018

· Assisted making IoT lamp with Arduino

Sept. 2018

Work Experience _____

Silikal Korea Construction Chemicals Co., Ltd.

Seoul, South Korea

INTERN

May 2018 - Jul. 2018

· Done internship program with logistics, sales, and accounting.

Silikal GmbH Mainhausen, Germany

INTERN Feb. 2018 - Apr. 2018

• Done internship program at sales & sales support in Export, Import division.

Honors & Awards

2022	Attendance Scholarship, ICWSM-2022 Grant Program	ICWSM
2022	EDIC Fellowship, A one-year PhD fellowship	EPFL
2021	Attendance Scholarship, ICWSM-2021 Grant Program	ICWSM
2020	Bachelor's Degree Linked Master Program Scholarship, Full tuition of last semester of undergraduate	SKKU
2019	Travel Scholarship, Language Exchange student @ Okayama University	Campus Asia
2019	Academic Excellence Scholarship, 70% of tuition from Dept. of Social Science (GPA:4.4/4.5)	SKKU

Academic Services _____

2022	Student Volunteer, ICWSM'22 Virtual Conference	ICWSM
2022	Student Volunteer, FAccT'22 On-Site Conference	FAccT
2022	Reviewer, Reviewed papers @ alt.chi track	CHI
2021	Student Volunteer, NAACL HLT'21 Virtual Conference	NAACL

Skills

Programming Python, SPSS, LaTeX, JAVA, C
Machine Learning Tensorflow, Keras, Pytorch
HTML, CSS, Node.js

User Research Interviewing, Conducting surveys, Experimental Design

Languages Korean, English, Japanese, French